<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../entries2html.xsl" ?>
<entry name="accordion" namespace="fn" type="Widget" widgetnamespace="ui">
	<desc>Convert a pair of headers and content panels into an accordion.</desc>
	<longdesc>
		<p>Make the selected elements Accordion widgets.</p>
		<p>The markup of your accordion container needs pairs of headers and content panels:</p>

		<pre><![CDATA[
<div id="accordion">
	<h3>First header</h3>
	<div>First content panel</div>
	<h3>Second header</h3>
	<div>Second content panel</div>
</div>
		]]></pre>

		<p>Accordions support arbitrary markup, but each content panel must always be the next sibling after its associated header. See the <a href="#option-header"><code>header</code></a> option for information on how to use custom markup structures.</p>
		<p>The panels can be activated programmatically by setting the <a href="#option-active"><code>active</code></a> option..</p>

		<p>This widget requires some functional CSS, otherwise it won't work. If you build a custom theme, use the widget's specific CSS file as a starting point.</p>
	</longdesc>
	<created>1.0</created>
	<options>
		<option name="active" default="0">
			<desc>
				The zero-based index of the panel that is active (open). A negative value select panels going backward from the last panel.
				<p>When the <a href="#option-collapsible"><code>collapsible</code></a> option is set to <code>true</code>, a value of <code>false</code> closes the accordion; otherwise nothing happens.</p>
			</desc>
			<type name="Boolean" />
			<type name="Number" />
		</option>
		<option name="animate" default="{}">
			<desc>
				If and how to animate changing panels:
				<ul>
					<li><code>String</code>: Name of easing to use with default duration.</li>
					<li><code>Number</code>: Duration in milliseconds with default easing.</li>
					<li><code>Object</code>: Animation settings with <code>easing</code> and <code>duration</code> properties.
						<ul>
							<li>Can also contain a <code>down</code> property with any of the above options.</li>
							<li>"Down" animations occur when the panel being activated has a lower index than the currently active panel.</li>
						</ul>
					</li>
					<li><code>null</code>/<code>false</code>: Disables animation.</li>
				</ul>
			</desc>
			<type name="Boolean" />
			<type name="Number" />
			<type name="Object" />
			<type name="String" />
		</option>
		<option name="collapsible" default="false">
			<desc>Whether all the sections can be closed at once. Allows collapsing the active section.</desc>
			<type name="Boolean" />
		</option>
		<widget-inherit id="widget-disabled" />
		<option name="event" default='"click"'>
			<desc>The event that accordion headers will react to in order to activate the associated panel. Multiple events can be specificed, separated by a space.</desc>
			<type name="String" />
		</option>
		<option name="header" default='"> li > :first-child,> :not(li):even"'>
			<desc>
				Selector for the header element.
				<p>Must be a selector that applies to the accordion container element, via <code>.find()</code>.</p>
				<p>The default covers both <code>ul</code>/<code>li</code> accordions, as well as flat structures like <code>dl</code>/<code>dt</code>/<code>dd</code>.</p>
			</desc>
			<type name="String" />
		</option>
		<option name="heightStyle" default='"auto"'>
			<desc>
				Controls the height of the accordion and each panel. Possible values:
				<ul>
					<li><code>"auto"</code>: All panels will be set to the height of the tallest panel.</li>
					<li><code>"fill"</code>: Expand to the available height based on the accordion's parent height.</li>
					<li><code>"content"</code>: each panel will be only as tall as its content.</li>
				</ul>
			</desc>
			<type name="String" />
		</option>
		<option name="icons" default='{ "header": "ui-icon-triangle-1-e", "headerSelected": "ui-icon-triangle-1-s" }'>
			<desc>
				Icons to use for headers, matching an icon defined by the jQuery UI CSS Framework. Set to <code>false</code> to have no icons displayed.
				<ul>
					<li>header (string, default: "ui-icon-triangle-1-e")</li>
					<li>activeHeader (string, default: "ui-icon-triangle-1-s")</li>
				</ul>
			</desc>
			<type name="Object" />
		</option>
	</options>
	<events>
		<event name="activate" type="accordionactivate">
			<desc>Triggered after a panel has been activated (after animation completes).</desc>
			<argument name="event" type="Event">
			</argument>
			<argument name="ui" type="Object">
				<property name="newHeader"></property>
				<property name="oldHeader"></property>
				<property name="newPanel"></property>
				<property name="oldPanel"></property>
			</argument>
		</event>
		<event name="beforeActivate" type="accordionbeforeactivate">
			<desc>Triggered directly after a panel is activated. Can be cancelled to prevent the panel from activating.</desc>
			<argument name="event" type="Event">
			</argument>
			<argument name="ui" type="Object">
				<property name="newHeader"></property>
				<property name="oldHeader"></property>
				<property name="newPanel"></property>
				<property name="oldPanel"></property>
			</argument>
		</event>
		<event name="create">
			<desc>
				Triggered when the accordion is created.
			</desc>
			<argument name="event" type="Event">
			</argument>
			<argument name="ui" type="Object">
				<property name="header"></property>
				<property name="panel"></property>
			</argument>
		</event>
	</events>
	<methods>
		<widget-inherit id="widget-destroy" />
		<widget-inherit id="widget-disable" />
		<widget-inherit id="widget-enable" />
		<widget-inherit id="widget-get-options" />
		<widget-inherit id="widget-get-option" />
		<widget-inherit id="widget-set-option" />
		<widget-inherit id="widget-set-options" />
		<method name="refresh">
			<desc>Recompute the height of the accordion panels. Results depend on the content and the <a href="#option-heightStyle"><code>heightStyle</code></a> option.</desc>
		</method>
		<widget-inherit id="widget-widget" />
	</methods>
	<example>
		<desc>A simple jQuery UI Accordion</desc>
		<code><![CDATA[
$( "#accordion" ).accordion();
]]></code>
		<html><![CDATA[
<div id="accordion">
	<h3>Section 1</h3>
	<div>
		<p>
		Mauris mauris ante, blandit et, ultrices a, suscipit eget, quam. Integer
		ut neque. Vivamus nisi metus, molestie vel, gravida in, condimentum sit
		amet, nunc. Nam a nibh. Donec suscipit eros. Nam mi. Proin viverra leo ut
		odio. Curabitur malesuada. Vestibulum a velit eu ante scelerisque vulputate.
		</p>
	</div>
	<h3>Section 2</h3>
	<div>
		<p>
		Sed non urna. Donec et ante. Phasellus eu ligula. Vestibulum sit amet
		purus. Vivamus hendrerit, dolor at aliquet laoreet, mauris turpis porttitor
		velit, faucibus interdum tellus libero ac justo. Vivamus non quam. In
		suscipit faucibus urna.
		</p>
	</div>
	<h3>Section 3</h3>
	<div>
		<p>
		Nam enim risus, molestie et, porta ac, aliquam ac, risus. Quisque lobortis.
		Phasellus pellentesque purus in massa. Aenean in pede. Phasellus ac libero
		ac tellus pellentesque semper. Sed ac felis. Sed commodo, magna quis
		lacinia ornare, quam ante aliquam nisi, eu iaculis leo purus venenatis dui.
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>List item one</li>
			<li>List item two</li>
			<li>List item three</li>
		</ul>
	</div>
	<h3>Section 4</h3>
	<div>
		<p>
		Cras dictum. Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus
		et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Vestibulum ante ipsum primis in
		faucibus orci luctus et ultrices posuere cubilia Curae; Aenean lacinia
		mauris vel est.
		</p>
		<p>
		Suspendisse eu nisl. Nullam ut libero. Integer dignissim consequat lectus.
		Class aptent taciti sociosqu ad litora torquent per conubia nostra, per
		inceptos himenaeos.
		</p>
	</div>
</div>
]]></html>
	</example>
	<category slug="widgets"/>
</entry>
