<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entry name="button" type="widget" widget-element="element visually representing the button">
	<title>Button Widget</title>
	<desc>Themeable buttons and button sets.</desc>
	<longdesc>
		<p>Button enhances standard form elements like buttons, inputs and anchors to themeable buttons with appropriate hover and active styles.</p>

		<p>In addition to basic push buttons, radio buttons and checkboxes (inputs of type radio and checkbox) can be converted to buttons. Their associated label is styled to appear as the button, while the underlying input is updated on click. For the association to work properly, give the input an <code>id</code> attribute, and refer to that in the label's <code>for</code> attribute. Don't nest the input inside the label, as that <a href="http://www.paciellogroup.com/blog/2011/07/html5-accessibility-chops-form-control-labeling/">causes accessibility problems</a>.</p>

		<p>In order to group radio buttons, Button also provides an additional widget, called Buttonset. Buttonset is used by selecting a container element (which contains the radio buttons) and calling <code>.buttonset()</code>. Buttonset will also provide visual grouping, and therefore should be used whenever you have a group of buttons. It works by selecting all descendants and applying <code>.button()</code> to them. You can enable and disable a button set, which will enable and disable all contained buttons. Destroying a button set also calls each button's <code>destroy</code> method. For grouped radio and checkbox buttons, it's recommended to use a <code>fieldset</code> with a <code>legend</code> to improve accessibility.</p>

		<p>When using an input of type button, submit or reset, support is limited to plain text labels with no icons.</p>

		<xi:include href="../includes/widget-theming.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>

		<ul>
			<li>
				<code>ui-button</code>: The DOM element that represents the button. This element will additionally have one of the following classes depending on the <a href="#option-text">text</a> and <a href="#option-icons">icons</a> option: <code>ui-button-text-only</code>, <code>ui-button-icon-only</code>, <code>ui-button-icons-only</code>, <code>ui-button-text-icons</code>.
				<ul>
					<li>
						<code>ui-button-icon-primary</code>: The element used to display the button's primary icon. This will only be present if a primary icon is provided in the <a href="#option-icons">icons</a> option.
					</li>
					<li>
						<code>ui-button-text</code>: The container around the textual content of the button.
					</li>
					<li>
						<code>ui-button-icon-secondary</code>: The element used to display the button's secondary icon. This will only be present if a secondary icon is provided in the <a href="#option-icons">icons</a> option.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</li>
			<li>
				<code>ui-buttonset</code>: The outer container of Buttonsets.
			</li>
		</ul>

		<h3>Dependencies</h3>
		<ul>
			<li><a href="/category/ui-core/">UI Core</a></li>
			<li><a href="/jQuery.widget/">Widget Factory</a></li>
		</ul>
	</longdesc>
	<note id="functional-css"/>
	<added>1.8</added>
	<options>
		<xi:include href="../includes/widget-option-disabled.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
		<option name="icons" default="{ primary: null, secondary: null }" example-value='{ primary: "ui-icon-gear", secondary: "ui-icon-triangle-1-s" }'>
			<desc>
				<p>Icons to display, with or without text (see <a href="#option-text"><code>text</code></a> option). By default, the primary icon is displayed on the left of the label text and the secondary is displayed on the right. The positioning can be controlled via CSS.</p>

				<p>The value for the <code>primary</code> and <code>secondary</code> properties must match <a href="/theming/icons/">an icon class name</a>, e.g., <code>"ui-icon-gear"</code>. For using only one icon: <code>icons: { primary: "ui-icon-locked" }</code>. For using two icons: <code>icons: { primary: "ui-icon-gear", secondary: "ui-icon-triangle-1-s" }</code>.</p>
			</desc>
			<type name="Object" />
		</option>
		<option name="label" default="null" example-value='"custom label"'>
			<desc>Text to show in the button. When not specified (<code>null</code>), the element's HTML content is used, or its <code>value</code> attribute if the element is an input element of type submit or reset, or the HTML content of the associated label element if the element is an input of type radio or checkbox.</desc>
			<type name="String" />
		</option>
		<option name="text" default="true" example-value="false">
			<desc>Whether to show the label. When set to <code>false</code> no text will be displayed, but the <a href="#options-icons"><code>icons</code></a> option must be enabled, otherwise the <code>text</code> option will be ignored.</desc>
			<type name="Boolean" />
		</option>
	</options>
	<events>
		<xi:include href="../includes/widget-event-create.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
	</events>
	<methods>
		<xi:include href="../includes/widget-method-destroy.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
		<xi:include href="../includes/widget-method-disable.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
		<xi:include href="../includes/widget-method-enable.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
		<method name="refresh">
			<desc>Refreshes the visual state of the button. Useful for updating button state after the native element's checked or disabled state is changed programmatically.</desc>
		</method>
		<xi:include href="../includes/widget-method-option.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
		<xi:include href="../includes/widget-method-widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2003/XInclude"/>
	</methods>
	<example>
		<height>100</height>
		<desc>A simple jQuery UI Button</desc>
		<code><![CDATA[
$( "button" ).button();
]]></code>
		<html><![CDATA[
<button>Button label</button>
]]></html>
	</example>
	<example>
		<height>100</height>
		<desc>A simple jQuery UI Buttonset</desc>
		<code><![CDATA[
$( "#radio" ).buttonset();
]]></code>
		<html><![CDATA[
<form>
	<fieldset>
		<legend>Favorite jQuery Project</legend>
		<div id="radio">
			<input type="radio" id="sizzle" name="project">
			<label for="sizzle">Sizzle</label>

			<input type="radio" id="qunit" name="project" checked="checked">
			<label for="qunit">QUnit</label>

			<input type="radio" id="color" name="project">
			<label for="color">Color</label>
		</div>
	</fieldset>
</form>
]]></html>
	</example>
	<category slug="widgets"/>
</entry>
